# CHIRANTAN GANGULY

41/4,Brindaban Mullick Lane, Kadamtala, Howrah, West Bengal, India 711101 (+91) 9330192247 • chirantanganguly01@gmail.com • www.linktr.ee/chirantan

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

- (i) Digital Signal Processing;
- (ii) Analysis and Interpretation of multi modal signals;
- (iii)Bio-Medical signal processing;
- (iv)Application of Machine Learning and Deep Learning in disease classification and prediction;
- (v)Applications of game theory in the study of complex systems.

#### Personal Profile

I am a second year Electronics and Communication Engineering undergraduate student at Institute of Radio Physics and Electronics, University of Calcutta, with a decent academic background. I am looking forward to work diligently under the able guidance of revered researchers, professors, to enhance my knowledge and experience in the field of Research & Development.

#### EDUCATION

#### University of Calcutta • Kolkata, India

August 2019 - Present

Bachelor of Technology • Electronics & Communication Engg. • CGPA: 9.79/10 Rank in Department – 1

St. Thomas' Church School • Howrah, West Bengal, India

2019

Class XII • Indian School Certificate Examination (ISC) • Percentage: 92.25%

St. Thomas' Church School • Howrah, West Bengal, India

2017

Class X • Indian Certificate of Secondary Education (ICSE) • Percentage : 95.6%

Work Experience

## Research Associate - Young Scientist Program (YSP)

June 2021 - Present

Blue Marble Space Institute of Science (BMSIS), Seattle, Washington, USA

- We look at the fundamentals of communication and information exchange from cells to animals to humans and artificial systems such as AI.
- We try to understand what is the role of communication for collective behavior in species and for the adaptation and selection of species in general.
- We will use information theory, agent-based modeling and natural language processing to analyze datasets such as dolphin languages or DNA signals.

## Summer Research Intern

May 2021 - Present

Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (C-DAC), Pune, Maharashtra, India

- Developed a well functioning ready to deploy video streaming web server, with both recorded video streaming, and live streaming abilities.
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Studied the functioning and relevance of H.264/MPEG-4 SVC video scalability standard after the deployment of 5G technology } \\$
- Side Projects:

Authoring Book Chapters on:

- (i) Application of Machine Learning Algorithms to study Mental Health during COVID'19 pandemic.
- (ii) Using Machine Learning to study Electronics Health Records (EHR) to answer relevant research questions related to COVID'19 pandemic.

## Positions of Responsibility

#### $\mathbf{Lead}$

Nov 2020 – Present

CodeClubCU(); - CodeClub of University of Calcutta (Supported by CodeChef)

- Teaching beginners about Data Structure and Algorithms, and increasing Code Literacy in Campus.
- Setting and testing problems for intra and inter college coding contests
- Hosting various talk events organised by CodeClubCU(); with distinguished Alumnus and Leaders in the Industry
- Appointing and managing Executive Team Members of CodeClubCU();
- Growing the chapter by increasing reach.

## Technical Team Lead

Jun 2020 – Jan 2021

 $Hult\ Prize$ 

- Developed Hult Prize Campus Chapter Website for University of Calcutta
- Managed other members of the Technical Team

#### e-Yantra Robotics Competition

Mar 2021

IIT Bombay

- Programmed and simulated UR5 arms to work in fully automated warehouse scenarios
- Developed a dynamic dashboard using Web development techniques for dynamically updating and showing all relevant in formations required in a shipping scenario.
- Project Demonstration: www.youtube.com/watch?v=QIGFrAWsTJA
- Skills used: Python, ROS Melodic, Gazebo, Computer Vision, IOT, Ajax

## COVID'19 Automated Screening Machine

Sept 2020

Department of Biotechnology, Ministry of Science and Technology, Govt. of India

- Automated the temperature based screening task for COVID'19 screening.
- Detect and alert whenever a person is in between the range of 10cm to 20cm in front of the machine.
- Measures his/her temperature
- It should measure temperature only when someone is detected not all the time.
- If the temperature is high, then a buzzer & RED LED should be turned on, to alert Gatekeeper.
- If the temperature is normal, then it should turn on the GREEN LED.
- It should spray sanitizer whenever hands are placed below a knob/a fixed point
- Display all relevant things over the LCD & Serial Monitor simultaneously.
- Count of the number of person currently inside should be maintained and displayed properly.
- TinkerCAD Simulation Link: www.tinkercad.com/things/3I1yRh8UKWp

## Exploring BRFSS data

Jul 2020

- Used the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS) data to answer 3 research questions using data visualizations, using R programming Language.
- "Among non-institutionalized adults in the US, are there any differences in alcohol consumption between veterans and non-veterans. The results could indicate whether veterans are at a lower or higher risk of alcohol addiction."
- "Among non-institutionalized adults in the US, Is a respondent's Body Mass Index (BMI) affect their chances to get depressive disorders? Is there any difference between genders? "
- "Among non-institutionalized adults in the US, are there any differences in general health condition depending on the the income level of the individual."
- GitHub Repository: github.com/ChirantanGanguly/Exploring-BRFSS-data

#### TECHNICAL & COMMUNICATION SKILLS

- IDE: Visual Studio Code, Arduino, Lazarus
- Programming Languages: Python, R, MATLAB, C/C++, LaTeX
- $\bullet \ \ Softwares: \ MATLAB/Simulink, \ COMSOL, \ LTspice/Pspice, \ Gazebo, \ Microsoft \ Office$
- Natural Languages: English, Bengali, Hindi

### Selected Coursework

• Analog Electronics, Digital Electronics, Signal Analysis and System Design, Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Antennas and Radio Wave Propagation for Long Distance Communication, Analog Communication, Electronic Devices, Materials and Physical Electronics

### Profile Links

- LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/chirantan-ganguly
- Github: https://github.com/ChirantanGanguly

Last updated: June 01, 2021